So, in this lab,
En este lab
we tried out TF transform.
probamos tf.Transform.
The reason that we're using TF transform is that it allows
Lo usamos porque nos permite
us to carry out preprocessing using Apache Beam,
realizar el procesamiento previo con Apache Beam
but do the preprocessing in TensorFlow.
pero ejecutarlo en TensorFlow.
The idea is that we can create
La idea es crear conjuntos de datos
preprocess datasets at scale during training and during evaluation.
de procesamiento previo a escala durante el entrenamiento y la evaluación.
Then we can turn around and apply that preprocessing
Y luego podemos aplicar ese procesamiento previo
on data that comes in for predictions,
en los datos que ingresan para las predicciones
and we can carry that out as part of a TensorFlow graph itself.
y lo podemos hacer como parte del gráfico de TensorFlow.
So, let's look at how that's done.
Veamos cómo se hace.
The first thing is that TensorFlow transformer is not part of core TensorFlow,
Primero, tf.Transform no es parte de TensorFlow en sí
it is an open-source library,
es una biblioteca de código abierto
but it's a separate library.
pero es una biblioteca independiente.
So, in order to do that,
Entonces, primero
I will go ahead and first install a specific version of transfer transform.
voy a instalar una versión específica de TensorFlow Transform.
So, we have to realize which version of TensorFlow we're
Debemos ver qué versión de TensorFlow
using and the corresponding version of TensorFlow transform.
estamos usando y la versión correspondiente de tf.Transform.
Now, when I recorded this video,
Cuando grabé este video
I was using TensorFlow 1.5 and
usaba TensorFlow 1.5
the corresponding version of TensorFlow transform for TensorFlow 1.5,
y la versión correspondiente de tf.Transform
was transfer transform 0.5.
era tf.Transform 0.5.
When you are doing it, it might be different.
Es posible que esto cambie cuando lo hagan ustedes.
The notebook, we will keep it up to date so that you will have the right version
Actualizaremos el notebook para que tenga la versión correcta
corresponding to the right version of TensorFlow that's installed in the notebooks.
correspondiente a la versión de TensorFlow instalada en los notebooks.
So, in this case, I'm basically going to install TensorFlow transform
En este caso, instalaré tf.Transform 0.5
0.5 and I'm going to install the package Apache Beam-GCP.
e instalaré el paquete Apache Beam [GCP].
Again, just to make sure that we get everything correct.
Para asegurarnos de que todo se comprenda bien
That already comes with Dataflow,
viene con Dataflow
we'll uninstall it because Apache Beam-GCP and Google Cloud Dataflow,
lo desinstalaremos porque Apache Beam [GCP] y Google Cloud Dataflow,
they're essentially the same thing.
son esencialmente lo mismo.
But in this case,
Pero, en este caso
we will just go with all of the open-source things.
usaremos solo los elementos de código abierto.
So, I'll go ahead and do a pip uninstall and a pip install.
Usaré "pip uninstall" y "pip install".
This is probably going to take a few minutes and once that's done,
Demorará unos minutos y cuando finalice
we want to make sure that the notebook picks up the new pip packages.
nos aseguraremos de que el notebook seleccione los paquetes de pip correctos.
The way you do this,
Para hacerlo
is to go ahead and click Reset.
hay que seleccionar Reset.
So, we have to wait for this filled circle to become open again.
Debemos esperar a que el circulo negro se habilite
That means that this particular cell has finished
es decir, que esta celda termine
executing and the appropriate pip installs are done.
de ejecutarse y las instalaciones de pip estén listas.
So, let's go ahead and wait.
Esperemos un momento.
All right. We're back. There it is,
Listo, finalizó.
this circle that was filled black is now open.
El círculo negro ahora está habilitado.
That means that this cell has completed.
Eso significa que la celda finalizó.
Actually, when you go ahead and look at the cell,
Si miramos la celda
you see that it has basically gone ahead and done a bunch of things.
podemos ver que ejecutó varios comandos.
you should see that it has uninstalled a bunch of things and installed a bunch of things.
debería ver que desinstaló algunas cosas e instaló otras
We do get the tents for transform 0.5.
y obtenemos tf.Transform 0.5.
So, but let's make sure.
Entonces…
So, what we could do here is,
Lo que podemos hacer primero
first of all, we want to make sure that it gets picked up.
es asegurarnos que se seleccione.
So, in order to do that,
Para ello
we will have to reset.
debemos restablecer.
So, I'm clicking the Reset,
Hago clic en Reset
restarting the session, and at this point,
para reiniciar la sesión
the new pip packages will be picked up.
y ahora se seleccionarán los paquetes pip nuevos.
We can go down,
Podemos ir hacia abajo
and we have a cell that basically does a pip freeze
y hay una celda que dice "pip freeze"
that tells you what's present on
que dice lo que hay
the Docker container that's running the notebook and I'm grepping.
en el contenedor de Docker donde se ejecuta el notebook
I'm finding any package that has the word flow or the word Beam in it.
y uso "grep", en busca de un paquete con la palabra "flow" o "beam".
So, the vertical bar here is an R. So,
La barra vertical significa "o".
let me do that and we should basically see that both
Haré eso y deberíamos ver
TensorFlow transform and Apache Beam are installed,
TensorFlow Transform y Apache Beam instalados.
TensorFlow itself is installed.
TensorFlow está instalado
In this case, we seemed to have like Tensor Board and Apache airflow,
también está TensorBoard y Apache Airflow
even though we don't need either of those.
aunque no los necesitamos.
But they're there. So, we have that.
Pero están allí.
Now, we are ready to basically import TensorFlow,
Ahora podemos importar TensorFlow
importance over transformers TFT,
con "import tensorflow_transform as tft"
and then make sure that you change
y luego hay que asegurarse de cambiar
your bucket in your project to reflect your Quick Labs project.
el depósito de su proyecto al depósito de Qwiklabs.
I've already done this.
Eso ya lo hice.
So, I will go ahead and run that cell and makes sure that it can be picked up by Bash.
Ahora, ejecutaré esa celda y me aseguraré de que
Make sure that my project and my compute region reflect this project and this region.
Me aseguro de que el proyecto y región de computación sean correctos.
The next thing that we want to do,
Lo próximo que haré
is to basically get our data from BigQuery.
es obtener los datos de BigQuery.
But unlike the previous example,
Pero a diferencia del ejemplo anterior
we're not doing any more filtering on latitude,
no vamos a filtrar la latitud, la longitud, etc.
longitude, et cetera, we will do that filtering in Apache Beam.
sino que filtraremos con Apache Beam.
That way, we'll make sure if somebody gives us,
Así, no aseguramos de que, si durante las predicciones,
Okay? So, we'll basically just go ahead and pick up a few things.
Vamos a seleccionar algunas cosas.
We'll do some preprocessing here to get the fare amount, et cetera.
Haremos un procesamiento previo para obtener el importe de la tarifa, etc.
But the query itself is much simpler than work as before.
Pero la consulta será más simple aquí
Because we'll carry out quite a bit of that preprocessing in Apache Beam.
porque hicimos algo del procesamiento en Apache Beam.
We'll go ahead and this time,
Esta vez, vamos a crear
I will create a DataFrame valid.
un marco de datos válido
Just to show you what happens.
para mostrarle lo que sucede.
I'm running the query,
Ejecuto la consulta
I'm executing it, creating a Pandas DataFrame,
y creo un marco de datos de Panda
and once I have the Pandas DataFrame,
y una vez que está listo
I'm calling head which shows me the first few lines.
voy a llamar "head" que nos darás las primeras líneas
Then I'm calling describe,
y llamaré "describe"
which will give me the mean and other statistics,
que me dará el promedio y otras estadísticas
mean, standard deviation, and the quantiles of this particular DataFrame.
como la desviación estándar y los cuantiles de este marco de datos en particular.
So, we have our DataFrame valid and we see that it basically has,
Ahora tenemos nuestro "df_valid" y, como puede ver
no 11,181 columns of fare amount,
tiene 11,181 columnas de importes de tarifa
hour of day, et cetera.
hora del día, etc.
we now see that the query is correct.
Podemos ver que la consulta es correcta.
So, let's now use this query to create a machine learning dataset,
así que la usaremos para crear un conjunto de datos de aprendizaje automático.
this time using TF transform and using Dataflow.
Esta vez uso tf.Transform y Dataflow.
Unlike every Dataflow job that we've done so far,
A diferencia del trabajo de Dataflow que hicimos
we now need an extra package to be installed on the machines that run Dataflow.
ahora debo instalar un paquete adicional en las máquinas para ejecutar Dataflow.
The way we do this,
Para hacerlo
is to basically write a requirements.text.
escribo un "requirements.txt".
So, remember that when we did a pip install, we basically said,
Recuerde que en la instalación de pip
pip install, TensorFlow transform 0.5.0.
usamos TensorFlow Transform 0.5.0.
Well, that's exactly what we do here.
Eso es lo que haremos aquí.
We go to, we write a requirements.text.
Escribimos "requirements.txt"
In the requirements.text, we say that we want to install TensorFlow transform 0.5.0.
En este archivo, indicamos que queremos instalar TensorFlow Transform 0.5.0
Having written the requirements.text,
Y ahora que escribimos el archivo de requisitos
we can now run our dataflow job passing in this requirements.text as a requirements file.
podemos ejecutar nuestro trabajo de Dataflow
So, this tells Dataflow that it needs to go through
Esto le indica a Dataflow que debe pasar por el archivo de requisitos
What is that we're doing in this job?
¿Qué estamos haciendo en este trabajo?
In this job as with the previous jobs,
En este trabajo, al igual que en los anteriores
we are going to be basically reading from BigQuery,
vamos a leer desde BigQuery
we are going to be creating records.
vamos a crear registros.
But unlike the previous case,
Pero a diferencia de antes
we created CSV records, in this case,
cuando creamos registros en CSV
we're going to create TensorFlow examples
en este caso, voy a crear ejemplos de TensorFlow
because they are more efficient. So, how does this work?
porque son más eficientes.
We also need to create the training dataset in the evaluation dataset.
También crearemos el conjunto de datos de entrenamiento y el conjunto de evaluación
So, let's walk through this piece by piece.
Veamos esto paso a paso.
The first thing is to decide what kind of preprocessing we want to do.
Lo primero es decidir qué tipo de procesamiento previo queremos hacer.
Okay. So, if you want to do two types of preprocessing,
Hay dos tipos de procesamiento previo
one type of preprocessing,
un tipo sirve si queremos verificar
Given a dictionary of inputs,
Lo que obtenemos de BigQuery
what we get from BigQuery is going to be a dictionary and conveniently,
es un diccionario de entradas
So, the same code is going to work both on
Así que el mismo código funcionará
the BigQuery dataset and on the JSON that comes in. So, what are we going to do?
en el conjunto de datos de BigQuery y en el de JSON.
We're going to get the inputs,
Vamos a obtener entradas
the pickuplon, the dropofflon, the pickuplat,
la longitud de recogida y destino la latitud de recogida y destino
the day of the week, all of these things,
el día de la semana, etc.
we're going to try to get them.
Intentaremos obtener todo esto
If any of them we're not able to get,
pero si no pudiéramos obtener alguna
we'll basically say it's not valid, right?
diremos que no es válida.
So, we're doing a try, except.
Así que usaremos "try" y "except".
So, we're going to basically do all of these things.
Procesaremos todo esto
If any of them throws an exception,
y si alguna entrada es una excepción
we basically say this isn't valid.
diremos que no es válida.
Having gotten them, we then basically say it is valid if all of these conditions are met.
Cuando las obtengamos, diremos que es válida
If the fare amount is greater than 2.5,
Si la tarifa es mayor que 2.5
and the pickup longitude is greater than negative 78, et cetera.
la longitud de recogida es mayor que -78, etc.
So, all of these tests,
En todas estas pruebas
if they all pass,
si todas son correctas
then the inputs are valid.
las entradas serán válidas.
Now, for the preprocessing.
Para el procesamiento previo
Now we're going to take our data and we're going to basically do
tomaremos los datos
things to make the neural network training better.
y mejoraremos el entrenamiento de la red neuronal.
So what are we going to do?
¿Qué haremos?
We're going to basically take the inputs fair amount and pass it through unchanged.
Tomaremos las entradas de tarifas y las pasaremos sin cambios.
If I could just say inputs fair amount or I could basically call some other function,
Pueden ser las tarifas o cualquier otra función como esta.
like in this case, I'm calling TF identity, just pass it through.
En este caso, llamo "tf.identity".
The day of the week is an integer.
El día de la semana es un número entero.
What BigQuery gives us an integer like 1,2,3,4.
BigQuery nos da un número entero como 1, 2, 3, 4.
In the previous lab,
En el lab anterior
for the feature engineering lab,
de ingeniería de funciones
and we did this, what did we do?
¿qué hicimos?
We essentially hard-coded in the vocabulary.
Lo ingresamos hard-coded en el vocabulario.
In this case, we're basically going to tell TensorFlow Transform,
En este caso, le indicaremos a TensorFlow Transform
go learn the vocabulary from the training dataset.
que aprenda el vocabulario de un conjunto de datos de entrenamiento.
but we know that whatever comes in during prediction,
pero sabemos que lo que se obtenga de la predicción
will automatically get converted.
se convertirá automáticamente.
So we're going to take the day of the week and we're going to convert that string that
Tomaremos el día de la semana y convertiremos esa string
we get into an integer based on the vocabulary.
en un número entero en base al vocabulario.
That's what the string to int does.
Eso es lo que hace "string_to_int".
The hour of day is already an integer,
La hora del día ya es un número entero
so we just pass it through unchanged.
así que la pasamos sin cambios.
The pickup lawn is a floating point number.
La longitud de recogida es un número de punto flotante
So we could also use it unchanged,
así que lo podemos usar sin cambios
but we know that neural network training works a lot better,
pero sabemos que el entrenamiento de redes neuronales funciona mejor
gradient descent works a lot better if our input values are small numbers,
y el descenso de gradientes funciona mejor
if they're in the range for example, zero to one.
si están en el rango de, por ejemplo, cero a uno.
So that's what we're asking TensorFlow Transform to do.
Eso es lo que queremos que haga TensorFlow Transform
TensorFlow Transform scale this value from zero to one.
que ajuste este valor de cero a uno.
But remember, in order to scale it from zero to one,
Recuerde que para ajustar de cero a uno
TensorFlow Transform needs to know what the minimum is and what the maximum is.
TensorFlow Transform debe conocer el valor mínimo y el máximo.
It will learn it from the dataset.
Lo obtendrá del conjunto de datos.
That's why we have the two phases.
Por eso tenemos las dos fases
We have the analyze phase and then we have the transform phase.
tenemos la fase de análisis y la fase de transformación.
So even though we're just writing that transform here scale zero to one,
Entonces, aunque escribimos que Transform ajuste de cero a uno
scale zero to one knows that in order to do this in the analyze phase,
sabe que para hacerlo en la fase de análisis
it has to find the min and the max.
debe encontrar el valor mínimo y el máximo.
So we do the same thing for all of these things,
Hacemos lo mismo para todos los elementos
and then we cast inputs that passengers to be a float,
y luego configuramos "cast (inputs ['passengers']"
and then we basically take the inputs.passengers and we basically do at once like this.
y en las entradas de pasajeros usamos "ones_like"
So we basically get an equal number of ones and then cast it to be a string.
para obtener una cantidad igual de unos y los transmitimos como una string.
So in this case, all of our keys are essentially the stringed one.
En este caso, todas nuestras claves son en esencia la string 1.
But this is just to give you an example of the fact
Pero es solo un ejemplo
that you can call arbitrary TensorFlow functions.
de que puede llamar funciones de TensorFlow arbitrarias.
Key thing is pre-processing is all TensorFlow functions.
Lo clave es que el procesamiento previo sean todas funciones de TensorFlow.
So having done that we also do engineering.
Una vez que terminamos aplicamos ingeniería
Right? Again, TensorFlow functions, so in this case,
nuevamente con las funciones de TensorFlow.
I'm taking the pickup lat, drop-off lat,
En este caso, tomo las latitudes de recogida y destino
subtracting them, and then taking the lat def and
y de destino y las extraigo.
the lawn def that is computed and also scaling it.
Luego, tomo la diferencia de latitud y longitud calculadas y las ajusto.
So again, we don't need to worry about what the difference,
No tenemos que preocuparnos
That's TensorFlow Transform's job to figure out
TensorFlow Transform averigua
what the min and max are to scale it appropriately.
cuál es el mínimo y máximo para el ajuste correcto.
Again, we then go ahead and take
Luego, tomo estos valores ajustados
these scaled values and then compute the Euclidean distance off the scaled values.
y los proceso con la distancia euclidiana de los valores ajustados.
We don't need to scale this again because we
No tenemos que volver a ajustarlos
know that if the distances are between zero and one,
porque sabemos que si las distancias están entre cero y uno
then this square root will also be between zero and one.
la raíz cuadrada también será de entre cero y uno.
Actually, it could be a slightly more.
De hecho, podría ser de un poco más
It will be 1.4 if both of them are one. But close enough.
como de 1.4 si ambos son 1, pero está cerca.
They're small numbers, so we don't need to scale it, and at this point,
Son número pequeños, entonces no debemos ajustar.
we basically have all of the pre-processing done, the pre-processing function.
Ahora que la función de procesamiento previo está lista.
So- but we still need to call the is valid method and the pre-process TFT method.
Aún debemos llamar al método "is_valid" y al método "preprocess_tft".
We have to call both of these methods from within the beam transform.
Llamamos a ambos métodos desde la transformación de Beam.
So how did we do that?
¿Cómo lo hacemos?
The way we do this is we first
Primero, configuramos los metadatos
set up the metadata for the raw data that we are going to be reading it.
de los datos sin procesar que vamos a leer.
What's a raw data?
¿qué son los datos sin procesar?
This is the data that comes from BigQuery.
Son los datos que vienen de BigQuery.
So we basically say that the day of the week and the key,
Digamos que el día de la semana y la clave
they're both strings, and the fair amount,
son strings y el importe de la tarifa
the pickup lawn, pickup lat,
la longitud y latitud de recogida
all of these things are floats,
todas estas cosas, son puntos flotantes
and we basically create a raw data schema which
creamos un esquema de datos sin procesar
is essentially a dictionary that goes from
que es básicamente un diccionario
the name of the column to whether it's a string or it's a float or if it's an integer.
con el nombre de la columna, ya sea una string, un punto flotante o un número.
Hour of day and passengers, they're both integers.
La hora del día y los pasajeros son números enteros.
This is in the raw data.
Son datos sin procesar.
This is what comes out of BigQuery.
Esto proviene de BigQuery
So we take the raw data and we basically sell.
Tomamos los datos sin procesar
Let's go ahead and write the raw data metadata.
e indicamos que escriba los metadatos de los datos sin procesar.
We write that out so that
Lo escribimos para que la entrada de JSON
the JSON input that comes in from the user will also be of this raw data metadata.
que ingresa el usuario también pertenezca a estos metadatos de datos sin procesar.
So we basically is going to be of this form and we want
Es decir, que tenga esta forma
to let our serving input function notice.
y que lo note la función de entrada de entrega.
Then, we basically say,
Entonces, indicamos que
"Go ahead and read the data from BigQuery using the query that we've just
lea los datos de BigQuery con la consulta que creamos
created and filter it using the method is valid."
y los filtre con el método "is_valid".
So you see how it is valid method comes in.
Para esto sirve este método
It's being called as part of a beam filter.
Se llama como parte de un filtro de Beam.
The beam filter is carried out with the rules that we specified in the is valid function.
El filtro de Beam se usa con las reglas que especificamos en la función "is_valid".
Then, we basically call,
Así, llamamos
analyze, and transform dataset.
"AnalizeAndTransformDataset".
When we do that, we have to specify the transformation function.
Debemos especificar la función de transformación.
The transformation function is pre-process underscore TFT.
Esta función es "preprocess_tft"
This is a one that does all the scaling, etc.
es la que hace el ajuste.
So at this point, we basically get back the transform dataset and the transform function,
Ahora, recibimos el conjunto de datos transformado y la función de transformación
and what we do is that we take the transform data and we write it out as TF records.
y tomamos "transformed_data" y lo escribimos como "tf.record"
We write it out as TF records that are Gzipped,
con el sufijo .gz
compressed to save space.
es decir, comprimidos para ahorrar espacio.
Then we do the same thing for the test data.
Hacemos lo mismo con los datos de prueba.
So in the training data,
En los datos de entrenamiento
I created the query at one,
creé una consulta de 1
and in the test data, I created query at two,
y en los datos de prueba cree la consulta de 2
and the way I set up my query was that depending on whether one or two was passed in,
para configurarla, indiqué que según si pasa 1 o 2
that was a phase.
esa es la fase
I either picked up the first few of the hash buckets or the last of the hash buckets.
tomo las primeras líneas de los depósitos de hash o las últimas líneas.
So that's how I'm getting my training dataset or evaluation dataset.
Así obtengo mi conjunto de datos de entrenamiento o de evaluación.
So having done that,
Una vez que hicimos eso
I now write out my transform
escribo mi conjunto de datos
the test dataset and also write them out to the evaluation stuff and finally,
de prueba transformado y también lo escribo en la evaluación.
and this is very important,
Esto es muy importante
we have to write out the metadata of the transformations.
tenemos que escribir los metadatos de las transformaciones.
This is how all of the TF methods that we called,
Así, todos los métodos de TF que llamamos
they get stored in the graph.
se almacenan en el gráfico.
So what this does is that it actually writes out a model.
Lo que hace es escribir un modelo.
A model actually isn't something that you train,
Un modelo no es algo que entrena
but it's a model that consists of TensorFlow operations that are going to
sino que está compuesto de operaciones de TensorFlow
get put in front of your normal model graph so that
que se colocaran enfrente del gráfico del modelo normal
any inputs that come in from the user go through
para que las entradas que ingrese el usuario
the TensorFlow Transform of TensorFlow functions into your normal model.
pasen por las funciones de transformación de TensorFlow hacia su modelo normal.
So with this, we are now ready and we can basically go
Con esto, estamos listos
ahead and create a pre-process dataset.
para crear un conjunto de datos de procesamiento previo.
If I set this to be true,
Si lo configuro como verdadero
I would create a small dataset but I'm setting it to be false.
crearé un pequeño conjunto de datos pero lo configuraré como falso.
dataflow and it is going to basically go ahead and create it.
y lo creará.
get an error that says that the Dataflow API is not enabled,
Si vuelve a recibir el error de que la API de Dataflow no está habilitada
go to the quick clubs project and enable the dataflow API and having done that,
vaya al proyecto de Qwiklabs y habilítela.
this dataflow job should get launched and once this is done,
Así, el trabajo de Dataflow debería iniciarse y cuando finalice
you should be able to see files in the pre-process TFT.
debería poder ver los archivos en preprocess.tft.
Once that's done, then the training is very similar to what existed earlier.
Cuando termine, el entrenamiento es parecido al que había antes
But let's go and look at it.
pero veámoslo
Let's look at what's actually different.
busquemos las diferencias.
So when we look at TensorFlow Transform under taxifare_tft,
Veamos la transformación de TensorFlow debajo de "taxifare.txt"
let's go look at model.pi,
y abramos "model.py"
and in the model.pi, what is different?
¿Cuál es la diferencia aquí?
So we basically get our input columns the same way as before.
Las columnas de entrada están igual que antes.
We're bucketizing, we're feature crossing,
La agrupación en depósitos, la ingeniería de funciones
we are creating a white columns,
se crearon las columnas amplias
we're creating a deep columns.
y las columnas profundas
All this is identical to the way we did our preprocessing.
todo esto es idéntico a lo que había antes del procesamiento previo
Earlier, when we did it with DataFlow and we actually had
cuando lo hicimos con Dataflow.
an extra ad engineered function that we remember to call for all three places.
También teníamos una función de ingeniería adicional que llamamos para tres lugares.
In this case though,
En este caso
we don't need to do that, we don't have this ad engineered function.
no necesitamos hacer eso. No tenemos la función de ingeniería adicional
TensorFlow Transform is now doing inherently as part of the graph.
ahora lo hace TensorFlow Transform como parte del gráfico.
So what we're basically saying is,
Indicamos que
when somebody gives me a serving function,
cuando alguien me da una función de entrega
I'm basically going to go ahead and read out of
leeré desde esta función de transformación
this transform function all of these operations that have been performed,
todas las operaciones que realizamos
take the raw data that comes in,
tomaré los datos sin procesar
so these are the raw data,
que ingresa, que son estos
and then basically apply everything that happens in TensorFlow Transform function,
y aplicaré todo lo que sucede en la función TensorFlow Transform,
all of these things that we did.
todo lo que hicimos.
Essentially all of the code that we called in pre-process_tft,
Es decir, todo el código que llamamos en "preprocess.tft".
we're basically saying apply all of those to my features,
Le indicamos que aplique eso a mis funciones
to my feature placeholder.
en el marcador de posición de mi función.
So apply them to the feature placeholders,
Lo aplico en los marcadores de posición
get back the features,
obtiene los atributos
and that is now the pair of things that we return.
y ahora ese es el par de elementos que obtenemos.
The feature placeholders is what the end-user gives us,
Los marcadores de posición de atributos es lo que nos proporciona el usuario
the stuff that was in the JSON.
lo que estaba en JSON.
The features is a result of taking what was in the JSON and
Los atributos son el resultado de tomar lo que estaba en JSON
applying all of that TensorFlow Transform transformation function,
y aplicarlo en la función de transformación tf.transform.
All of those operations do
Aplica todas esas operaciones
the feature placeholders and that's essentially what gets returned.
en los marcadores de posición de atributos y muestra eso.
At this point, we have the serving input function.
Ahora, tenemos una función de entrada de entrega.
Now when we are reading the dataset, what do we have to do?
Cuando leemos el conjunto de datos ¿qué tenemos que hacer?
we have to apply these transformations.
tenemos que aplicar estas transformaciones.
Luckily though, we don't have to write that code ourselves because
Por suerte, no tenemos que escribir ese código
an input function maker that you can basically go and say,
tiene un compositor de funciones de entrada
"Please build me a training input function that
al que le pedimos que cree una función de entrada de entrenamiento
applies all of the stuff in the transform metadata.",
que aplique todo esto en "transformed_metadata"
and now go ahead and read it with Gzip and that's pretty much it.
y que lo lea con gzip y eso es todo.
It comes with the built training input function
Tiene una función de entrada de entrenamiento incorporada
that knows how to read TensorFlow records.
que sabe cómo leer los registros de TensorFlow.
So we don't have to write the whole normal code that we would write,
Así que no tenemos que escribir todo el código que necesitaríamos
where would read a dataset,
para leer un conjunto de datos
and we'd apply a decode CSV.
y aplicar un CSV para decodificar
All of that stuff completely goes away.
todo eso no es necesario.
We essentially just use
Simplemente usamos la función
the build training input function to essentially do the job for us.
de entrada de entrenamiento para que haga el trabajo.
The train and evaluate is exactly the same as before.
El entrenamiento y la evaluación son iguales que antes
We create a train spec,
creamos "train_spec"
we create an eval spec,
creamos "eval_spec"
and we pass in the estimator,
y pasamos el estimador
the train spec and the eval spec.
"train_spec" y eval_spec".
The one difference was that because were you reading Gzip,
La diferencia es que como leemos Gzip
we passed in a Gzip reader function,
la función de lectura es Gzip.
and the Gzip reader function is essentially a TF record reader that basically reads Gzip,
que es un "TFRecordReader" que lee Gzip.
and that's essentially it.
Eso es todo.